# SEAN RYAN FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Creative and driven front-end developer with extensive professional experience in digital marketing and communications. My goal is to be a standout member of a forward-thinking development team by combining my talent for writing clean and intuitive code with stellar communication skills.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Types of Non-voters Quiz Source Code | View Live

An interactive election-related quiz built for the creative studio 13milliseconds

- Developed a guiz using React that categorizes users into 'types of non-voters'
- Wrote logic to score and track possible quiz results throughout a user session
- Implemented a UI design from a wireframe using Sass and styled components

# Think Tank Source Code | App Hosted on Netlify

A real-time chat application build with React and Firebase

- Implemented a Firebase Realtime Database to store and relate user, room, and message data objects
- Connected database to an interface allowing users to perform create, read and delete operations via the Firebase API

# Pickipedia Source Code | App Hosted on Heroku

A Wikipedia-style app for chronicling live American roots music in NYC

- Built a full-stack MVC-style application allowing users to create a profile and perform CRUD operation on wikis
- Implemented different access rights and privileges for "basic" and "premium" user roles
- Wrote unit and integration tests with Jasmine

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Freelance Web Developer, Nov. 2019 – Present

Various Clients

- Léieren Learning Systems: Develop custom landing pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript on the Cornerstone On Demand CMS
- 13milliseconds: Develop custom functionality and landing pages with React

#### Digital Communications Coordinator, Sept. 2015 - Present

Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY

- Hand code and troubleshoot responsive, cross-client HTML emails for various member communications
- Build a set of internal user interfaces for ACM employees to interact with the redesigned ACM Digital Library using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Write social media, web, and email marketing content tailored to an audience of software engineers and computing researchers
- Doubled average monthly social follower growth, tripled monthly Google AdWords member acquisitions

#### Project Manager, Feb. 2012 - Sept. 2015

SIS International Research, New York, NY

- Managed multi-city qualitative and quantitative research projects through initial planning to client delivery; wrote and delivered final reports to clients
- Moderated focus groups and in-depth interviews for research projects in cities across the US

# GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Blog

seanpryan89@gmail.com (203) 731-4234 www.seanpryan.dev

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

**JavaScript** 

ES6

CSS3

HTML5

**Bootstrap** 

**jQuery** 

**Responsive Design** 

Sass

Git

**GitHub** 

React

**NPM** 

Webpack

Node.js

**Express** 

**Unit Testing** 

SQL

Sequelize ORM

**MongoDB** 

Postares

Deployment (Heroku/Netlify)

# **EDUCATION**

#### Bloc

Nov. 2018 - July 2019

Completed Web Developer Track Program

# NYU Continuing Education (Front-end Foundations)

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018
Front-end end web development with an emphasis on mobile first layout techniques

#### **Hamilton College**

Aug. 2007 - May 2011

Degree: B.A. in History, English

Literature